Next, we need to unzip the file,
بعد ذلك، نحتاج إلى فك ضغط الملف،
then open the extracted files so that we can see and work with the data inside.
ثم افتح الملفات المستخرجة حتى نتمكن من رؤية البيانات التي بداخلها والعمل عليها.
We'll do both programmatically and therefore reproducibly,
سنقوم بالأمرين؛ برمجيًا وبالتالي قابل للتكرار،
and we'll do both in our Jupyter Notebook.
وسنقوم بالأمرين على تطبيق Jupyter notebook.
So first things first,
لذا، الأهم فالمهم،
we need to open up a Jupyter Notebook.
نحن بحاجة إلى فتح تطبيق Jupyter notebook.
We can do that by typing Jupyter Notebook in
يمكننا فعل ذلك عن طريق كتابة تطبيق Jupyter notebook في
our terminal on Mac or Linux or command prompt on PC.
وحدتنا الطرفية على نظامي Mac أو Linux أو موجه الأوامر على الكمبيوتر الشخصي.
Before we do that though,
لكن قبل أن نفعل ذلك،
a notebook server will start in whatever directory we run this command in,
سيبدأ خادم دفتر الملاحظات بالعمل في أي دليل نشغل فيه هذا الأمر،
which means any notebook files will be saved in that directory.
مما يعني أن ملفات دفتر الملاحظات ستُحفظ في هذا الدليل.
And external files like our downloaded data set,
والملفات الخارجية مثل مجموعة بياناتنا التي تم تنزيلها،
are most easily imported when in this directory.
يكون استيرادها أكثر سهولة عندما تكون في هذا الدليل.
So I'm going to navigate to the folder I want to work in which is called
إذًا، سأنتقل إلى الملف الذي أرغب في العمل عليه والذي يسمى
data wrangling which is within a folder in my documents called Udacity.
data wrangling الموجود داخل مجلد يسمى Udacity في "مستنداتي".
So from my home directory,
لذا من الدليل الرئيسي،
all changed directories or cd to documents,
كل الأدلة المتغيرة أو cd إلى المستندات،
then cd to Udacity and finally change directories to data wrangling.
ثم cd إلى Udacity وأخيرًا تغيير الدلائل إلىdata wrangling.
And now we can enter our Jupyter Notebook command.
والآن يمكننا أن ندخل أمر تطبيق Jupyter notebook.
Okay. So here we can see our Jupyter Notebook dashboard
حسنًا. والآن يمكننا رؤية لوحة معلومات Jupyter Notebook
which shows a list of the notebooks,
التي تعرض قائمة من دفاتر الملاحظات
files and sub-directories in the directory where the notebook server was started.
والملفات والدلائل الفرعية في الدليل حيث بدأ خادم دفتر الملاحظات.
Here we can create new notebooks by clicking New in Python
يمكننا إنشاء دفاتر ملاحظات جديدة بالنقر فوق New في Python3
3 or you can use
أو يمكنك استخدام
the wrangling template notebook that's available for download which I put in this folder,
قوالب دفتر ملاحظات المعالجة المتاحة للتنزيل والتي أضعها داخل هذا المجلد،
which you can see here.
الذي يمكنكم رؤيته هنا.
Side note: IPYNB stands for I Python Notebook,
ملاحظة جانبية: IPYNB يرمز إلى I Python Notebook،
which is the old name for Jupyter Notebooks.
وهو الاسم القديم لتطبيق Jupyter notebook.
And I'll click that. And there we go.
وسأنقر فوقه. وها نحن نكمل الدرس.
We've opened up a Jupyter Notebook.
لقد فتحنا تطبيق Jupyter notebook.